Date of birth: 15th February 1982

Nationality: French

ORCID: 0000-0001-9006-8436

NIH BioSketch

Github organization: github.com/IARCbioinfo

Website: www.rarecancersgenomics.com

Computational Cancers Genomics Team
Genomic Epidemiology Branch
International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO)
25 avenue Tony Garnier, 69007 Lyon, France

Email: follm@iarc.who.int

Research Group: www.iarc.who.int/teams-ccg/

Professional Appointments

2021-on	Team Leader, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), Lyon, France
2014-2020	Scientist, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), Lyon, France
2012-2014	Staff Research Scientist, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, Lausanne, Switzerland
2007-2012	Postdoctoral Researcher Institute of Ecology and Evolution University of Berne Switzerland

Honors and awards

2024-on	Member of the WHO classification of turmours 6 th edition subcommittee on computational pathology, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), tumourclassification.iarc.who.int/										
2023	Young investigator award, International Mesothelioma Interest Group (iMig), imig.org										
2022-2024	Chair of the of the Rare Cancers Working Group , European Prospective Investigation into Cancer and Nutrition (EPIC), epic.iarc.who.int										
2021-on	lung NET task force member, European NEuroendocrine Tumors Society (ENETS), www.enets.org										
2016-on	Scientific Committee member , French MESOBANK (virtual mesothelioma national biobank), www.netmeso.fr/netmeso/mesopath-et-mesobank										

Education

2004-2007	PhD	in	Population	Genetics	and	Evolution,	University	of	Grenoble,	France.
theses.hal.science/tel-00216192/										

2001–2004 **MSc Computer science and Applied Mathematics, specialization in Bioinformatics**, Grenoble Institute of Technology ENSIMAG, Grenoble, France.

Personal Statement

After studying applied mathematics and computer science, I completed a Ph.D. in population genetics and bioinformatics in 2007. During this time I gained a strong expertise in statistical genetics and bioinformatics methods, and I wrote several software now widely used in the field. After my PhD., I moved to the University of Berne as a postdoctoral researcher where I started to work more specifically on large human genomic data. I developed in particular several Bayesian models to identify genetic variants associated with phenotypes observed in different human populations or ethnic groups, being the consequence of local adaptation. In 2012, I was recruited as a Staff Research Scientist in the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology of Lausanne where I worked on new statistical and bioinformatics methods for the analysis Next Generation Sequencing data. In 2014 I been recruited as a staff scientist to develop computation cancer genomics projects and to coordinate the bioinformatics efforts in the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO). I am particularly involved in the molecular characterisation of thoracic tumors like lung neuroendocrine neoplams and malignant mesothelioma. In 2016, Dr. Lynnette Fernandez-Cuesta and I launched the Rare Cancers Genomics initiative, and and since 2021 we have been co-leading the IARC Computational Cancers Genomics team.

Publications

81 publications in international peer-reviewed scientific journals, including 9 publications as first/co-first author, and 15 publications as last/co-last/corresponding author.

14'125 total citations, h-index: 43 (source: Google Scholar). Full list available at Google Scholar and My NCBI Bibliography.